RG 009:006, Abele vs. Markle
Connecticut State Library
- Series 1. Legal Documents, 1966-1973
  - Answer - United States District Court District of Connecticut, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Appearances, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Appellees extension of time & motion to dismiss, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Appellees' renewal of their motion for an expedited appeal, No. 72-730, 1972 December 13 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Application for stay of execution of judgment of three-judge District Court for the District of Connecticut - Supreme Court of the United States, Civil Action No. B-521, circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bill of costs, Case Nos. 72-730 & 72-56, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bond for costs on appeal, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brief for the appellees, No. 71-1605, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Brief RE: defendants' motion to quash, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brief - draft, crica 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Briefs - printed and typed, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Certificate of counsel; complaint; exhibits; and affidavits, Civil Action No. 14291, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Coercive effect of the present judgment - supplemental memorandum of defendants, Docket No. MR-5241, 1972 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Decision of United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, 1972 May (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Defendants' Memorandum, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Defendants' pleadings, Civil Action No. 14291, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Defendants' Response to Plaintiffs' Objections, Civil Action No. B-521, circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Denial of Application for Stay of Execution, A-360, 1972 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Denial of Stay - United States Supreme Court, No A-1187, 1972 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Deposition - Nelson, Frieda, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 July 25 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Drafts, circa 1971-1972, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Index to record on appeal; index to supplement to record on appeal, Civil Action No. B-521, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Judgment; Joint Notice of Appeal; Order; Bond for Costs on Appeal, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 April-May (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Judgment file, Civil Action Nos. 14291 and B-521, 1973 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Judgment - United States District Court District of Connecticut, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Jurisdiction - supplemental memorandum of defendants, Docket No. MR-5241, 1972 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Jurisdictional statement of appellants, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - List of affidavits and articles, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Memorandum in opposition to pettitioners application for stay of execution, 1972 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Memorandum in support of motion to intervene on behalf of Connecticut Citizens Right to Life Committee, Inc., Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Memorandum in support of motion for stay of execution, Civil Action No. 14291, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Memorandum of appellants in support of stay of execution - United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, Civil No. 14291, 1972 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Memorandum of costs and disbursements, Case Action No. 14291, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Memorandum of decision - United States District Court District of Connecticut, Civil No. 14291, 1972 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Memorandum of decision, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Memorandum of petitioners in support of stay of execution - statement of the case, No. MR-5241, 1972 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Motions, Civil Action No. 14291, circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Motion for contempt, to enforce injunction and for other relief; motion for immediate hearing; order to show cause to Meskill, Thomas J., Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 May 26 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Motion for enlargement of time, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 July 20 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Motion for extension of time, Docket No. 71-1605 and Civil Action No. 14291, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Motion for leave to file offer of proof, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 August 16 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Motion for leave to file supplemental affidavit, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Motion for ordering the names to be put under seal, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Motion for re-argument, 1972 June 6 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Motion to affirm, No. 72-730, circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Motion to dismiss appeal, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Motion to file further offer of proof concerning children aborted alive, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Motion to quash, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Motion to strike, Civil Action No. 14291, 1971 April 7 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - New York Hospital - Cornell Medical Center subpoena, affidavit, and notice of deposition, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Notice of appeal to Supreme Court of the United States, 1972 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Notice of deposition and amendment to notice of deposition, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Notice of hearing - United States District Court District of Connecticut, Civil No. 14291, 1972 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Notice of motion for stay of execution pending appeal; motion for stay of execution; Affidavit - Killian, Robert K., Civil No. 14291, 1972 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Objection to motion for summary judgment, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Opinion - United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, Docket No. 71-1605, 1971 December 13, undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Order - Supreme Court of the United States, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Order - United States District Court District of Connecticut, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Order and judgment, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Order and judgment; memorandum of decision - United States District Court District of Connecticut, Civil Action No. 14291, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Original complaint - United States District Court District of Connecticut, Civil Action No. 14291, 1971 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Per Curiam, Docket No. MR-5241, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Petition for rehearing, No. 71-1605, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Plaintiffs' pleadings, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Plaintiffs - appellants' brief and appendix, No. 71-1605, 1971 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Plaintiffs - appellants' brief and appendix, No. 71-1605, 1971 September 30 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pleadings, Civil Action No. 14291, 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pleadings, Civil Action Nos. B-521 and 14291, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pleadings, Civil No. 14291, 1972 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pleadings - Supreme Court of the United States, No. A-1187, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pleadings - United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Pleadings - United States District Court District of Connecticut, Civil Action No. 14291, circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Pre-Trial Order, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 June 12 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Proofs of briefs, circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Request to clerk to certify and transmit entire record, Civil Action No. B-521, 1972 October 20 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ruling on plaintiffs' motion to convene a three-judge District Court and for equitable relief; and defendants' motion to dismiss, Civil Action No. 14291, 1971 May 12 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Statement of the case, Civil No. 14291, 1972 May 4 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Subpoenas, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Summons, Civil Action No. 14291, 1971 March 3 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Supersedeas bond - Supreme Court of the United States, No. MR-5241, 1972 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Supplemental brief for appellees, Docket No. 71-1605, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - United States Supreme Court has granted stays in abortion cases - supplemental memorandum of defendants, Docket No. MR-5241, 1972 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Series 2. Exhibits, 1971-1972
  - Exhibit H - New York abortion situation, circa 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - List of exhibits, Civil Action No. B-521, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Plaintiffs' exhibit 1 for identification, circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series 3. Correspondence, 1970-1980
  - Correspondence - Archdiocese of Hartford, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General, 1970-1980 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General of Louisiana, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General of New Hampshire, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General of Rhode Island, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General of Tennessee, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General of Texas, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General of Utah, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence - Center for Disease Control, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence - Connecticut Catholic Conference, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence - Constituents, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence - Florida Senate, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence - Georgia Department of Law, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence - Health Department, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence - Hiltz Publishing Company, "Life or Death", circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence - The New York Legal Defense and Education Fund for the Unborn, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence - Pro-Life Council of Connecticut, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence - Roraback, Williams & Avery, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence - Senator Canulla, Guido J. (Rhode Island), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence - Office of the State's Attorney at Waterbury, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence - State Welfare Department, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence - Sweetman, Randy, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence - United States Court of Appeals Second Circuit, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence - United States District Court District of Connecticut, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence - United States Supreme Court, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence - The Value of Life Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Series 4. Subject Files, 1947-1981
  - Abortion - medical articles submitted to the court, circa 1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Abortion advice - General Assembly, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Abortion advice - Health Department, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Abortion cases - Hall M.D., et al. vs. Lefkowitz, et al.; depostion of George W. Corner, M.D., 1970 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Abortion cases - Roe, et al. vs. Wade; Doe, et al. vs. Bolton, et al., 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 52-53)
  - Abortion cases from other jurisdictions, circa 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Affidavits of non-physicians, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Affidavits of physicians, undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - After Supreme Court decision in Georgia and Texas cases, circa 1973 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Aftermath of abortion decision, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Appeal file - decision & judgment, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Assistant Attorney General opinions from various states, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Byrn brief - abortion, circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Byrn brief - abortion, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Calendars, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Case history, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Case notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Compelling state interests test, Virginia Law Review, circa 1972; photocopies (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut vs. Menillo, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut abortion statutes, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Doe v. Bolton, circa 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Doe vs. Randall, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Eisenstadt case, 1972 June 16 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Expense vouchers - abortion, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Experimentation with human beings, circa 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Hanrahan vs. Doe, et al.; Hefferman vs. Doe, et al., 1971 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Indiana abortion case, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Klein abortion case, U.S. District Court Eastern District of New York, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Liley, Dr. A.W., undated; photocopies (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous - abortion, 1947-1981, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous - abortion material, circa 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - National Doctors Brief; Bart Hefferman, M.D. (Illinois); amicus curiae, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - New Jersey abortion case, circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - New York application for temporary restraining order, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - North Dakota abortion legislation, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - North Dakota referendum, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Official records & reports, 1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Oral argument & reference material, circa 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Petitions protesting relaxation of abortion laws, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Photographs from Handbook on Abortion, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Poe vs. Norton, Civil No. 15712, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Proclamation of Special Session by Governor Meskill, 1972 May 13 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Reference materials, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Research material & drafts - United States Court of Appeals, circa 1971-1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Rhode Island abortion case & miscellaneous abortion material, circa 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Saine vs. Mulvey, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Shettles, Landrum B., undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - State of Connecticut vs. Maximino Villafane, 1972 June 19 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - State of Connecticut Circuit Court, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - State of North Dakota vs. H. Benjamin Munson, M.D., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Telephone numbers, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Tennessee Woman vs. Pack, circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - United States vs. Vuitch, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Weekly Bulletins on Abortion Program, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Wisconsin abortion appeal, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Wisconsin abortion case, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Series 5. Legislative Files, 1971-1975
  - Abortion - legislative history, circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Excerpts from H-110 Connecticut General Assembly, House Proceedings, Vol. 14 Part 3, 974-1450, circa 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - House Bill No. 6002 Public Act No. 1, 1972 May; photocopy (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Legislation - abortion, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Proposed regulations concerning abortions, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Series 6. Press Files, 1971-1974
  - Clippings, circa 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
  - Life or Death, circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Series 7. Publications, 1965-1978
  - Nilsson, Lennart and C. Wirsen. A Child is Born the Drama of Life before Birth. New York: Delacorte Press, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hilgers, Thomas W. and Dennis J. Horan. Abortion and Social Justice. New York: Sheed & Ward, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
  - The John Marshall Journal of Practice & Procedure. volume 9, number 2 Spring, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - One Hundred and Twenty-Second Registration Report. State of Connecticut, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - One Hundred and Twenty-Third Registration Report. State of Connecticut, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Prof. Robert M. Byrn's Challenge to the New York Abortion Law on Behalf of a Class of Unborn Children. Complete Motions and Briefs in Supreme Court of the United States., circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - The Public Health Code of the State of Connecticut and Other Department Regulations, 1978 April (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Respect Life Program: A Catholic Community Experience, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Series 8. Duplicates, 1971-1973
  - Hiltz Publishing Company, Life or Death, circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Legal documents, circa 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Legal documents, circa 1971-1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
  - Legislative files, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Proceedings - Supreme Court of the United States, No. A-1187, MR-5241, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)